Rishabh Gupta

Senior Software Engineer

I've spent the last 4 years learning things there is to know about the IT industry from developing an application to supporting it. I'm currently applying this knowledge in my role as Senior Software Engineer for Optum, where I'm responsible for Develop high-quality software using agile methodologies and providing guidance to the team.



rgv2109@gmail.com

8826289159

gurugram, India

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software EngineerOptum (UnitedHealth Group)

01/2020 - Present

Gurugram, INDIA

Software EngineerOptum (UnitedHealth Group)

01/2018 - 12/2019

Gurugram,INDIA

Associate Software Engineer UnitedHealth Group

06/2016 - 12/2017

Gurugram, INDIA

PROJECTS

Smart Audit Master (SAM) (06/2017 – Present)

 SAM Edit Rule is a web-based tool that enables specially trained quality analysts to develop and implement search parameters that catch possible defects in the claims processed on the various Platforms. Each edit rule defines search criteria that SAM applies to a daily download of claims.

Claims Highway (CHWY) (05/2019 - 02/2020)

 Claims Highway is a flexible, re-usable, enterprise-wide claim system architecture that simplifies system integrations and allows for common claims services to be shared by multiple systems, thereby increasing consistency and reducing costs.

eHP (esync health portal) (07/2016 - 06/2017)

Ehp is members end to end system for all UHC clients. My UHC
has over 9 billion users Ehp is front end for all core application
of UHC system. Ehp allows member to Register and check their
benefits, eligibility, account balances, Finding network doctor,
Estimate treatment costs and learn about health conditions,
symptoms and latest treatment options.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University

2012 - 2016

Higher Secondary Certificate – Class XII V.S.M.P.S, civil lines, Kanpur, India

2011 - 2012

Secondary School Certificate – Class X V.S.M.P.S, civil lines, Kanpur, India

2009 – 2010

SKILLS

Angular, Express.js, Node.js	
Python, Javascript	
Azure Cloud, AWS	
Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift	
ETL, SSIS, SSRS	• • • • •
Load Balancing, F5, Nginx	• • • • •
Microsoft SQL Server,MySQL	• • • • •
Jenkins, Ansible	• • • • •
Grafana, Splunk, Angelfish	• • • • •
GitHub , TFS	• • • • •
Jupyter, MS Studio, MS Visual C++	• • • • •

ACHIEVEMENTS

Make IT Happen

This award is given once a year who have exhibited outstanding performance in the year and contributed significantly to achieving company priorities. Got this award in 2019

Sustaining Edge Award - 31K ₹

This award is given for showing exceptional performance for a long period. Got 2 awards in 2019 and 1 award in 2018 and 2017

Star Award - 15K ₹

This award is given for showing high performance . Got this award each in last 4 years

Team Award - 15K ₹

This award is given for helping the team in order to archive their goal . Got this award each in last 2 years

LANGUAGES

Hindi Native or Bilingual Proficiency English

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Movies

series

Music

Cooking